M. ADITYA RAJA SEKHAR



madityarajasekhar@yahoo.in github.com/Mars3623

in linkedin.com/in/m-aditya-raja-sekhar/



+91 8297716190

ABOUT ME

Organized, top performer, and goal-driven individual with six months experience in working as a data engineering trainee, working on projects such as data warehousing. Skilled at developing reports, analyzing data, and identifying solutions to build a competitive advantage. Interested to work on complex projects, Innovate contributing ideas, and learning new things.

SKILL

Exploratory Data Analysis Programming language

- Python
- MySQL
- PySpark

Microsoft Excel

Data visualization Tools

- Tableau
- Power BI

Platforms or Tools

- AWS
- Azure Databricks
- Informatica IICS

Familiar With

Matlab

LANGUAGES

English Hindi Teluqu

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIPS

Accenture North America Data Analysis and Visualization Virtual Internship

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology- Mechatronics Engineering

SRM Institute of Science and Technology 2017 - 2021 PERCENTAGE: 81.42

Maths, Physics, Chemistry

Board of Intermidiate Education

2015 - 2017PERCENTAGE: 90.8

EXPERIENCE

Data Engneering Trainee, Achyutas Soft Pvt. Ltd.

2022 - PRESENT

- Worked on Projects involving Data Warehousing.
- · Worked with tools like Azure Databricks, AWS, and Informatica IICS.

Career Team Manager, I'ventors Initiatives Pvt. Ltd.

2020 - 2020

- Was the De-facto intermediate between various teams such as Marketing, PR, Business Development and Technical Development.
- Performed Data Analysis on user base which led to 86% platform retention.
- 5 times increase in overall user base from about 200 people to more than 1000 people.

PROJECTS

Election Data Warehousing

- Used Rest API to POST Data to AWS RDS in MySQL DataBase via. Lambda Function.
- AWS S3 was used as staging, Data was transferred using Databricks.
- After de-normalizing and applying SCD type-2 on stage data using Databricks, Data was stored in hive tables and later in S3.
- The entire process was automated by creating Jobs in Workflows.

Exploratory Data Analysis On Global Terrorism

- Used Python Libraries Such As Pandas for Data Analysis and Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Plotly for visualization.
- · Carried out univariate, bivariate, and multivariate analyses.